

SENIOR BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT & ACCOUNT SPECIALIST

Personal Profile

Battagorai Village, Kodanad post, Kotagiri The Nilgiris, 643217 India 8270801700 nishusharula@gmail.com

Links

Analytical and problem-solving skills (IQ test) report

LinkedIn

Skills

Microsoft Office

Business Analyst- Power BI

Team leadership

Lead & Demand Generation

Key Accounts Relationship

Business Development

CRM

Cold calls & email campaigns

Stakeholders Relationship Management

Product Demonstration & Presentation

Cross selling & Upselling

ERP, FMCG and Home Automation

Languages

English & Tamil

Professional Summary

Skilled in Analytical Skills, Communication, Creative Writing, Data Analytics, Marketing, Business Development and Problem Solving.

As a Customer Account Specialist (CAS), I develop and maintain customer relationships with buyers and provide support for questions related to: purchase orders, quotations, product inquiries, quality issues, and technical assistance.

Experienced Business Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the software services, home automation and FMCG industry.

Employment History

Nutrition Officer, Nestle India Ltd., Bangalore

02/2021 - 08/2021

Collaborate with stakeholders and provide key accounts with service, support and improvement opportunities to increase their consumption of a FMCG product or service and maximize retention, cross-sell and upsell opportunities via B2B

Product Specialist (Client Relationship), Nestle India Ltd., Bangalore

09/2021 - 07/2023

Building and maintaining profitable relationships with key customers. Overseeing the relationship with customers handled by your team. Managing the sales pipeline with key accounts and resolving key customer complaints quickly and efficiently. Keeping key customers updated on the latest products in order to generate leads and demand.

Education

10th, Riverside Public School, The Nilgiris

ICSE- 84%

12th, AVB Matriculation School, Coimbatore

State Board-89%

B.Tech Biotechnology, Karunya University, Coimbatore

CBCS-67%

Internships

Business Consultant, Curiosfly Automation

01/2020 - 01/2021

Driving business growth by fostering strong client relationships, delivering compelling presentations and demos, and executing effective negotiation strategies.

Courses

Business Analyst, Guvi IIT